Guide to the Julie Braun-Vogelstein Collection, 1743-1971 AR 25034 / MF 473
Center for Jewish History, Publisher.
Julie Braun-Vogelstein Collection
1743-1971
Braun-Vogelstein, Julie,
This collection contains correspondence and other materials related to the Braun-Vogelstein family.
35 linear feet.
AR 25034 / MF 473
Leo Baeck Institute Archives
Biographical Note
Born in Stettin (now Szczecin, Poland) on January 26, 1883, Julie Braun-Vogelstein became active in the Social Democratic movement, and was Heinrich Braun's secretary and his wife following the death of Lily Braun in 1916. Active as an author, art historian, and journalist, she emigrated to the United States via France in 1935-1936. She was a member of the board of the Leo Baeck Institute, and she died in New York City on February 6, 1971. She assembled and preserved the papers of various members of her family, which are included in her collection.
Heinrich Braun and Lily Braun: Born in Budapest on November 23, 1854, Braun studied law and economics at the Universities of Vienna and Strasbourg. He joined the Sozialdemokratische Partei Deutschlands (SPD) and worked as an editor and journalist, becoming a leading representative of the party's revisionist wing. Braun died in Berlin on February 9, 1927. Born Lily von Kretschman in Halberstadt on July 2, 1865, Lily Braun was a social worker and author, active in the German feminist movement and the SPD. She died in Berlin-Zehlendorf on August 9, 1916.
Otto Braun: Born in Berlin on June 27, 1897, the son of Heinrich and Lily Braun, Otto Braun died in combat in Marlecave, France, on April 29, 1918.
Ludwig Vogelstein: born in Pilsen, Austria-Hungary (now Plzen, Czechoslovakia), on February 3, 1871, Ludwig Vogelstein, the older brother of Julie Braun-Vogelstein, emigrated to the United States in 1896, becoming a successful entrepreneur and prominent American Jewish philanthropist. He died in New York City on September 23, 1934.
Heinemann Vogelstein: Born in Lage on February 13, 1841, Julie Braun-Vogelstein's father was a rabbi in Pilsen and Stettin, a leader of the liberal tendency in German Jewry, and a noted opponent of Zionism. He died in St. Moritz, Switzerland, on August 4, 1911.
Hans von Kretschman and Jenny von Gustedt: Lily Braun's father, Hans von Kretschman, was a general in the Prussian army. He was born in Berlin on August 11, 1832, and died there on March 31, 1899. Jenny von Gustedt, Lily Braun's grandmother, was born in Kassel on September 7, 1811, the illegitimate daughter of Jerome Bonaparte, king of Westphalia. She died in 1890.
Scope and Content Note
A. Heinrich and Lily Braun:
Correspondence of Heinrich Braun with individuals, including Victor Adler, August Bebel, Eduard Bernstein, Lujo Brentano, Benedetto Croce, Kurt Eisner, Sigmund Freud, Wolfgang Heine, Benno Karpeles, Karl Kautsky, Isolde Kurz, Friedrich Meinecke, Paul Natorp, Heinrich de Man, Walther Rathenau, Werner Sombart, Ferdinand Toennies, and Max Weber.
Correspondence of Lily Braun with individuals, including Mathilde von Colomb and Heinrich Braun.
Manuscripts, clippings, by and about Heinrich Braun and his political and journalistic activities, including minutes of the party court of the Frankfurt an der Oder-Lebus branch of the SPD concerning charges brought against him; related material from the SPD Congress in Dresden, 1903.
Photo; resume; clippings; script of radio speech on Heinrich Braun.
B. Otto Braun:
Juvenilia, memorabilia, and childhood and wartime correspondence of Otto Braun; material concerning Julie Braun-Vogelstein's biography of him, including correspondence and Lily Braun's diaries.
Otto Braun’s diaries are available on microfilm (1904-1911 on MM 91 and 1911-1914 on MM 102; 1904-1914 also on MF 473 Reel 40).
C. Ludwig Vogelstein:
Family and business correspondence; speeches on metallurgy and Jewish affairs; and photos of New York City in the early twentieth century, and of his business.
D. Julie Braun-Vogelstein:
Correspondence with family members and other individuals including Hasso von Seebach, Hannah Arendt, Ludwig Dehio, Henri de Man, Friedrich Meinecke, Eugen Rosenstock-Huessy, Toni Stolper, and Adam von Trott zu Solz.
Essays, research notes, manuscripts, and clippings on art history, politics, and philosophy, by Julie Braun-Vogelstein and others; proofs, drafts, and other material for her autobiography, and for biographies of Heinrich Braun, Otto Braun, and Ludwig Vogelstein.
Material on resistance to the Nazis, including a manuscript by Dietrich Bonhoeffer, and lists of individuals executed after July 20, 1944.
E. Heinemann and Rosa Vogelstein
Correspondence, including letters of Heinemann Vogelstein's wife, Rosa Vogelstein, as well as letters from other family members, colleagues, including Josef Heinemann, Siegmund Maybaum, Claude Montefiore, and N. A. Nobel, and organizations such as the Liberaler Rabbiner-Verband.
Sermons, pamphlets, and speeches concerning Zionism and other topics; autograph album; records of the Vereinigung fuer das liberale Judentum in Deutschland, and of the Liberaler Rabbiner-Verband.
Religious documents, including shechita certificates, marriage contracts, rabbinical court decrees concerning divorce, and eighteenth-century manuscript commentaries on the Bible and the Kabbalah.
F. Von Kretschman/Von Gusted Branch
Correspondence, including letters of Hans von Kretschman to his wife and letters of Jenny von Gustedt to individuals, including the German Empress Augusta, Ottilie von Goethe, and Wolfgang von Goethe.
Autobiographies, wills, genealogies, and diaries of members of the Gustedt and Kretschman families; the autobiography of Lily Braun's sister Maria von Kretschman (alias Maria de Victorica), and photocopies of the files of her trial for espionage by the U.S. Department of Justice after World War I.
See Inventory.
The following individuals are mentioned in this collection:
Adler, Victor; Arendt, Hannah; Augusta, German Empress; Bebel, August; Bernstein, Eduard; Bonhoeffer, Dietrich; Braun, Otto; Brentano, Lujo; Colomb, Mathilde von; Croce, Benedetto; Dehio, Ludwig; Eisner, Kurt; Freud, Sigmund; Goethe, Ottilie von; Goethe, Johann Wolfgang von; Gustedt, Jenny von; Haas, William S.; Heine, Wolfgang; Heinemann, Josef; Karpeles, Benno; Kautsky, Karl; Kretschman, Hans von; Kretschman, Maria von; Kurz, Isolde; Man, Heinrich de; Man, Henri de; Maybaum, Siegmund; Meinecke, Friedrich; Montefiore, Claude; Natorp, Paul; Neumark, Yisroel (Ernst); Nobel, Nehemias Anton; Rathenau, Walther; Rosenstock-Huessy, Eugen; Seebach, Hasso von; Sombart, Werner; Stolper, Toni; Thimme, Friedrich; Toennies, Ferdinand; Trott von, Adam; Trott zu Solz, Adam von; Victorica, Maria de (see Kretschman, Maria von); Vogelstein, Ludwig; Vogelstein, Heinemann; Vogelstein, Rosa; Weber, Max
Arrangement
Series I: Heinrich and Lily Braun
Series II: Otto Braun
Series III: Ludwig Vogelstein
Series IV: Julie Braun
Series V: Hermann and Rosa Vogelstein
Series VI: von Kretschmann and von Gusted Families
Series VII: Addenda
Microfilm
Collection is available on 121 reels of microfilm (MF 473).
Reel 1: 1/1-1/11
Reel 2: 1/12-1/20
Reel 3: 1/21-1/33
Reel 4: 1/34-1/44
Reel 5: 1/45-1/46
Reel 6: 2/47
Reel 7: 2/48-2/49
Reel 8: 2/50-2/56
Reel 9: 2/57-2/62
Reel 10: 2/63-2/70
Reel 11: 2/71-3/80
Reel 12: 3/81-3/84
Reel 13: 3/85-3/87
Reel 14: 3/88-3/92
Reel 15: 3/93-3/94
Reel 16: 3/95
Reel 17: 3/96
Reel 18: 4/97-4/99
Reel 19: 4/100-4/103
Reel 20: 4/104-4/106
Reel 21: 4/A 107 (11/5)-4/A 108
Reel 22: 4/A 109-4/A 110
Reel 23: 4/A 111-4/A 112
Reel 24: 4/A 113 (12/5)-5/A 114 (13/1)
Reel 25: 5/A 115 (13/2) - 5/A 116 (13/3)
Reel 26: 5/A 117 (13/4) - 5/A 118 (13/5)
Reel 27: 5/A 119 (13/6) - 5/A 123 (14/4)
Reel 28: 5/A 124 - 5/A 126
Reel 29: 5/A 127 - 5/A 129
Reel 30: 6/A/130 - 6/A/131
Reel 31: 6/A/132 - 6/A/133
Reel 32: 6/A/134 - 6/A/135
Reel 33: 6/A/136 - 6/A/140
Reel 34: 6/A/141 - 7/A/145
Reel 35: 7/A/145 - 7/A/153
Reel 36: 7/B/1 - 7/B/5
Reel 37: 7/B/6 - 7/B/9
Reel 38: 8/B/10 - 8/B/11
Reel 39: 8/B/12 - 8/B/15
Reel 40: 8/B/16 - 9/B/31
Reel 41: 9/B/32 - 9/B/34
Reel 42: 9/B/35 - 9/B/37
Reel 43: 9/B/38
Reel 44: 9/B/39
Reel 45: 9/B/40 - 9/B/41
Reel 46: 10/B 42 - 10/B 43
Reel 47: 10/B 44 - 10/B 47
Reel 48: 10/B 48 - 10/B 50
Reel 49: 10/B 51 - 10/B 55
Reel 50: 10/B 56 - 11/B 60
Reel 51: 11/B 61 - 11/B 65
Reel 52: 11/B 66 - 11/B 73
Reel 53: 11/B 74 - 12/C 7
Reel 54: 12/C 8 - 12/C 10
Reel 55: 12/C 11 - 12/C 22
Reel 56: 13/C 23 - 13/C 31
Reel 57: 13/C 32 - 13/C 37
Reel 58: 13/C 38 - 13/C 47
Reel 59: 14/C 48 - 14/C 54
Reel 60: 14/C 55 - 14/C 58
Reel 61: 14/C 59 - 14/C 60
Reel 62: 14/C 61 - 14/C 68
Reel 63: 14/C 69 - 15/C 73
Reel 64: 15/C 74 - 15/C 78
Reel 65: 15/C 79 - 15/C 80
Reel 66: 15/C 81 - 15/C 82
Reel 67: 15/C 83
Reel 68: 16/C 84
Reel 69: 16/C 85 - 16/C 86
Reel 70: 16/C 87 - 16/C 88
Reel 71: 16/C 89 - 16/C 97
Reel 72: 16/C 98 - 17/C 109
Reel 73: 17/C 110 - 18/C 130
Reel 74: 18/C 131 - 18/D 3
Reel 75: 18/D 4 - 18/D 9
Reel 76: 18/D 10 - 19/D 26
Reel 77: 19/D 27
Reel 78: 19/D 28 - 19/D 32
Reel 79: 19/D 33 - 20/D 49
Reel 80: 20/D 50 - 20/D 58
Reel 81: 20/D 59 - 20/D 72
Reel 82: 20/D 73 - 21/D 78
Reel 83: 21/D 79
Reel 84: 21/D 80 - 21/D 84
Reel 85: 21/D 85 - 21/D 90
Reel 86: 22/D 91 - 22/D 98
Reel 87: 22/D 99 - 22/D 106
Reel 88: 22/D 107 - 22/D 118
Reel 89: 22/D 119 - 23/D 127
Reel 90: 23/D 128 - 23/D 135
Reel 91: 23/D 136 - 23/D 144
Reel 92: 23/D 145 - 24/D 156
Reel 93: 24/D 157 - 24/D 169
Reel 94: 24/D 170 - 25/D 183
Reel 95: 25/D 184 - 25/D 191
Reel 96: 25/D 192 - 25/D 201
Reel 97: 25/D 202 - 26/D 209
Reel 98: 26/D 210 - 26/D 221
Reel 99: 26/D 222 - 26/D 231
Reel 100: 26/D 232 - 27/D 241
Reel 101: 27/D 242 - 27/D 248
Reel 102: 27/D 249 - 27/D 251
Reel 103: 27/D 252 - 28/D 259
Reel 104: 28/D 260 - 28/D 269
Reel 105: 28/D 270 - 28/D 276
Reel 106: 28/D 277 - 29/D 280
Reel 107: 29/D 281 - 29/D 290
Reel 108: 29/D 291 - 29/D 296
Reel 109: 29/D 297 - 30/D 302
Reel 110: 30/D 303 - 30/D 319
Reel 111: 30/D 320 - 31/D 329
Reel 112: 31/D 330 - 31/D 338
Reel 113: 31/D 339 - 31/D 348
Reel 114: 32/D 349 - 32/E 7
Reel 115: 32/E 8 - 32/E 14
Reel 116: 32/E 15 - 32/E 21
Reel 117: 33/E 22 - 33/E 25
Reel 118: 33/E 26 - 33/E 33
Reel 119: 33/E 34 - 33/F 5
Reel 120: 33/F 6 - 34/F 13
Reel 121: 34/F 14 - 34/F 21
Separated Material
Photographs have been removed to the LBI Photograph Collection.
Access Restrictions
Collection is microfilmed (except for Boxes 35 and 36), use MF 473 (121 reels).
Materials can only be used at the LBI in New York, no loans.
Access Information
Readers may access the collection by visiting the Lillian Goldman Reading Room at the Center for Jewish History. We recommend reserving the collection in advance; please visit the LBI Online Catalog and click on the "Request" button.
Other Finding Aid
33-page inventory.
See individual reel records for inventory.
Bibliography
Memoir microfilm reel # 91, 102
Braun, Julie (Vogelstein), 1883-1971; Vogelstein, Heinemann, 1841-1911; Vogelstein, Ludwig, 1871-1934; Braun Otto, 1897-1918; Braun, Lily (von Kretschman) von Gizycki, 1865-1916; Kretschman, Hans von, 1832-1899; Female author; Anti-Nazi movements in Germany; Anti-Nazi movements outside Germany; Anti-Zionism; Diaries; Divorce; Domestic life; 19th cent.; Domestic life; 20th cent.; Emigration and immigration; 1871-1933; Emigration and immigration; 1933-1945; USA; Feminism; Germany--Politics and government--1871-1918; Germany--Politics and government--1918-1933; Germany; history; Allied Occupation; 1945 -; Internment of aliens; Reform Judaism; Jewish law; Judaism; Nazi Germany; political repression; Autograph albums; Professions and occupations; art historians; Professions and occupations; authors; Professions and occupations; industrialists; Professions and occupations; journalists; Professions and occupations; politicians; Professions and occupations; rabbis; Restitution and indemnification claims (1933- ); Sermons; Socialism; Theresienstadt (Concentration or internment camps); Women; politics; World War, 1914-1918; World War, 1914 - 1918; espionage; World War, 1939 -1945; resistance; Sozialdemokratische Partei Deutschlands (SPD); Frankfurt/Oder; Liberaler Rabbiner-Verband; Vereinigung fuer das liberale Judentum in Deutschland; New York (City); Wills and testaments; Concentration or internment camps; Military service; World War, 1914 - 1918; Business and economic history; Philosophy, Jewish; Professions and occupations; lawyers; Professions and occupations; historians; Professions and occupations; editors; Professions and occupations; economists; Genealogy; Family trees; Prayers; Poems; Christian-Jewish dialogue; Decrees; Vital statistics; Marriage; Voyages and travels; France
Container List
The following section contains a detailed listing of the materials in the collection.
Folder numbering resets with each new series, rather than with each new box. Old box and folder numbers are shown in parentheses.
- Series I: Heinrich and Lily Braun, undated, 1800s-1900s
  - (1/1): Julie Braun-Vogelstein: Inventory, 1967-1980 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Heinrich and Lily Braun Correspondence with Victor Adler, 97 letters, 14.Sep.1891- 13.Oct, 1908 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Heinrich and Lily BraunCorrespondence with Victor Adler, 1892-1908 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Julie Braun-Vogelstein correspondence with Victor Adler, 1932 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Heinrich Braun Correspondence to Emma Adler (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Heinrich Braun, Correspondence w/ Althoff, Schmidt-Ott, Pasz Kowsk, 1908-1931 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Julie Braun-Vogelstein, Correspondence Arons-Adler 1893-1895, Julie Braun-Vogelstein from Arons, 1933, 1893-1895, 1933 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Julie Braun-Vogelstein and Heinrich Braun, Correspondence with Auschuetz, Aufr, Vogelstein, Arons, 1896-1906, 1917, 1929, 1931 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Heinrich Braun, Correspondence w/ F.Braun, Brentano, Buroach, Barth, 1894-1897, 1906-1907, 1921 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Julie Braun-Vogelstein and Heinrich Braun, Correspondence w/ Stephan Bauer, 1897-1913, 1928 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Julie Braun-Vogelstein, Correspondence w/Bebel and Lily v.Gizycki, Frieda Simon, 1896-1912, 1931 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Julie Braun-Vogelstein and Heinrich Braun, Correspondence w/ Becker, Dr.Benecke, Prof.Weber, 1918-1931 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Heinrich Braun, Correspondence w/Bernstein, w/Newspapers, 1900-1901, 1914-1916 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Julie Braun-Vogelstein and Heinrich Braun, Correspondence w/ Adolph Braun (Mohr Verlag), etc., 1927-28 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Julie Braun-Vogelstein and Heinrich Braun, Correspondence w/ Bernhard Goehre, v. Gruber and Guttman and Gradnauer, 1895, 1902-1923, 1927-1929 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Heinrich Braun, Correspondence w/ David, Dehio, Dombrowski, 1895-1929 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Heinrich Braun, Correspondence w/Eisner, Engel, Fuchs, 1887,1895-96,1905-1912 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Julie Braun-Vogelstein and Heinrich Braun, Correspondence w/ K.Haenisch, Becker, Eckert, A.Weber, Schulze, v.Borthiexicz, 1916-1923 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Julie Braun-Vogelstein and Heinrich Braun, Correspondence w/ Heine, Herkner, 1894-1911, 1924, 1927-1931 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - (2/1): Julie Braun-Vogelstein and Heinrich Braun, Correspondence w/Benno Karpeles, 1891-1919 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Julie Braun-Vogelstein and Heinrich Braun, Correspondence w/Karl Kautsk, 1885-1888, 1894, 1922, 1927-28, 1931 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Julie Braun-Vogelstein and Heinrich Braun, Correspondence w/ Timm, Kampfmeyer, Kulturrat, Kramer, 1918, 1922-1923, 1931 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Julie Braun-Vogelstein and Heinrich Braun, Correspondence w/ I.Kurz B.Croce, Benito Mussolini, 1922-1926 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Julie Braun-Vogelstein and Heinrich Braun, Correspondence Adler to Lazardelle, Lang, H.Lederer, C.Legien, Leser (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Julie Braun-Vogelstein:Heinrich Braun,correspondence Liebknecht, (1891missing) 1899 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Julia Braun-Vogelstein correspondence K.Marx to Cugelmann, 1877 (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Julie Braun-Vogelstein and Heinrich Braun, correspondence Meyer, Mehring, Merton, Millerand, Mombert, Dr.Much (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Julie Braun-Vogelstein and Heinrich Braun, correspondence w/F.Meinecke, 1916-7, 1928 (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Julie Braun-Vogelstein and Heinrich Braun, correspondence Natorp, Natorp re: Lipiner, Lipiner, Nathan, 1881, 1914, 1916-17, 1927 (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - Julie Braun-Vogelstein and Heinrich Braun, correspondence w/ Oncken, 1918, 1928, 1932 (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - Julie Braun-Vogelstein and Heinrich Braun, correspondence w/Philippowitsch, Plenge, Posadowski, 1896, 1911, 1928 (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - Julie Braun-Vogelstein and Heinrich Braun, correspondence w/ Prof.Petzoldt, 1909-26 (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - Julie Braun-Vogelstein and Heinrich Braun, correspondence w/ G.Radburch, Rathenau, Richanoff, Ruebenstrunk, Quarck (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - Julie Braun-Vogelstein and Heinrich Braun, correspondence Paul Singer, 1909-1911 (Box 1, Folder 33)
  - Julie Braun-Vogelstein and Heinrich Braun, correspondence Schmidt, Schulze, Gaevernitz, Verlag Springer, Stampfer, Stein, Schmidt- Ott, 1897, 1916-25, 1927-1929, 1931 (Box 1, Folder 34)
  - Julie Braun-Vogelstein and Heinrich Braun, Correspondence + articles W.Sombart, 1898-99, 1906-31 (Box 1, Folder 35)
  - Julie Braun-Vogelstein and Heinrich Braun, correspondence Peter von Struve, 1895-1904 (Box 1, Folder 36)
  - (3/1): Julie Braun-Vogelstein and Heinrich Braun, correspondence Dr. Siegmund Freud, 1927 (Box 1, Folder 37)
  - Julie Braun-Vogelstein and Heinrich Braun, correspondence /autographs, inc. Freud, A.Braun, B.Croce, K.Eisner, Brentano, etc., 1891-1939 (Box 1, Folder 38)
  - Julie Braun-Vogelstein and Heinrich Braun, correspondence F. Thimme, Adler, H.Teschemacher, Will Thorne, 1896, 1923, 1928, 1933 (Box 1, Folder 39)
  - Julie Braun-Vogelstein and Heinrich Braun, correspondence F.Toennis, 1894-1919,1928 (Box 1, Folder 40)
  - Julie Braun-Vogelstein and Heinrich Braun, correspondence w/ Leon Trotsky and Adler, 1912 (Box 1, Folder 41)
  - Julie Braun-Vogelstein and Heinrich Braun, correspondence w/ E.Adler, E.Braun, L.Braun, 1927; 1930. (Box 1, Folder 42)
  - Julie Braun-Vogelstein and Heinrich Braun, correspondence Hans Vaihinger, von Vollmar- Z, 1895; 1903-1907; 1913; 1918; 1922. (Box 1, Folder 43)
  - Julie Braun-Vogelstein and Heinrich Braun, Periodicals and Publications, Excerpts, Original, Photocopies, 1893-1894; 1897. (Box 1, Folder 44)
  - (4/1) Julie Braun-Vogelstein and Heinrich Braun, correspondence: Werner Sombart, 1888-1894. (Box 1, Folder 45)
  - (4/2) Julia Braun Vogelstein and Heinrich Braun, correspondence: Werner Sombart, 1895-1897. (Box 1, Folder 46)
  - (4/3) Heinrich Braun correspondence w/ Werner Sombat, 1898-1907 (Box 2, Folder 47)
  - (4/4) Heinrich Braun correspondence w/ Paul Natorp, 1879-1921 (N. Braun; 1880-1914) (Box 2, Folder 48)
  - (4/5) Julie Braun-Vogelstein correspondence: Friedrich Adler, 1932 (Box 2, Folder 49)
  - (5/1) Julie Braun-Vogelstein correspondence, periodicals, reviews, 1932-1933 (Box 2, Folder 50)
  - (5/2) Julie Braun-Vogelstein and Heinrich Braun newspaper clippings, reviews, 1897 (Box 2, Folder 51)
  - (5/3) Julie Braun-Vogelstein and Heinrich Braun correspondence, publishing w/agreements and corrections (Box 2, Folder 52)
  - (5/4) Julie Braun-Vogelstein and Heinrich Braun correspondence, clippings, 1924 (Box 2, Folder 53)
  - (5/5) Julie Braun-Vogelstein and Heinrich Braun reviews, periodicals, clippings, 1913 (Box 2, Folder 54)
  - (5/6) Julie Braun-Vogelstein and Heinrich Braun 2 articles by, 1892; 1894. (Box 2, Folder 55)
  - (5/7) Julie Braun-Vogelstein and Heinrich Braun articles about, correspondence, clippings, periodicals (Box 2, Folder 56)
  - (5/8) Julie Braun-Vogelstein correspondence re. Heinrich Braun, 1932-1933. (Box 2, Folder 57)
  - (5/9) Julie Braun-Vogelstein correspondence Gesellschaft, 1919 -1930 (Box 2, Folder 58)
  - (5/10) Julie Braun-Vogelstein and Heinrich Braun correspondence w/Fanny Lindheimer, 1902-1903 (Box 2, Folder 59)
  - (5/11) Julie Braun-Vogelstein and Heinrich Braun documents, diplomas, identity cards, 1884; 1919-1927. (Box 2, Folder 60)
  - (5/12) Julie Braun-Vogelstein reviews, 1967-1970. (Box 2, Folder 61)
  - (5/13) Julie Braun-Vogelstein reviews, clippings, 1903 (not refoldered). (Box 2, Folder 62)
  - (6/1) Julie Braun-Vogelstein and Heinrich Braun Articles (1887), 1903-1926 (Box 2, Folder 63)
  - (6/2) Julie Braun-Vogelstein ReichsTag resolution, correspondence, 1874-1904. (Box 2, Folder 64)
  - (6/3) Julie Braun-Vogelstein and Heinrich Braun Minutes, Clippings, 1903-1910 (n.r.) (Box 2, Folder 65)
  - (6/4) Julie Braun-Vogelstein and Heinrich Braun Correspondence, Clippings, 1903-1904 (n.r) (Box 2, Folder 66)
  - (6/5) Julie Braun-Vogelstein and Heinrich Braun Articles, 1887 (n.r. !!) (Box 2, Folder 67)
  - (6/6) Julie Braun-Vogelstein and Heinrich Braun Die Neue Gesellschaft, Correspondence etc., 1903-1906; 1916 (n.r.!!) (Box 2, Folder 68)
  - (6/7) Julie Braun-Vogelstein and Heinrich Braun Clippings, Correspondence etc, 1900-1909 (Box 2, Folder 69)
  - (6/8) Julie Braun-Vogelstein and Heinrich Braun Placards, HandBills, Clippings, 1902-1903 (Box 2, Folder 70)
  - (6/9) Julie Braun-Vogelstein and Heinrich Braun Correspondence, Legal Proceedings, 1903-1904 (Box 2, Folder 71)
  - Julie Braun-Vogelstein and Heinrich Braun Scrap Book, Obituaries HB, 1927 (Box 2, Folder 72)
  - (7/1) Julie Braun-Vogelstein and Heinrich Braun Correspondence, Arthur Silbergleit, 1921-1923 Felix Braun; 1920-1926 (n.r.) (Box 2, Folder 73)
  - (7/2) Julie Braun-Vogelstein and Heinrich Braun Correspondence, Raloff, K.Asch, von Maken, 1923-1926 (n.r.) (Box 2, Folder 74)
  - (7/3) Heinrich Braun to A. Fritzsche, 1922-24 (Box 2, Folder 75)
  - (7/4) Julie Braun-Vogelstein and Heinrich Braun Correspondence A.Fritzsche, 1922-24. (Box 2, Folder 76)
  - (7/4): Julie Braun-Vogelstein and Heinrich Braun correspondence Carl Scharbau (Box 3, Folder 76)
  - (7/5): Julie Braun-Vogelstein and Heinrich Braun Correspondence, 1921-23 (n.r.) (Box 3, Folder 77)
  - (7/6): Julie Braun-Vogelstein and Heinrich Braun correspondence Schiller Stiftung, 1922-1923 (Box 3, Folder 78)
  - (7/7): Julie Braun-Vogelstein and Heinrich Braun correspondence, F.Engels 1888-95; H.Schlueter 1886; F.Thimme, 1917-199[sic], 1933-34. (Box 3, Folder 79)
  - (7/8): Julie Braun-Vogelstein and Heinrich Braun Correspondence, 1919-1926 (n.r.!) (Box 3, Folder 80)
  - (7/9): Julie Braun-Vogelstein and Heinrich Braun Correspondence, Schuetzling, 1920-1924 (n.r.) (Box 3, Folder 81)
  - (7/10): Julie Braun-Vogelstein and Heinrich Braun Correspondence, Weltadressbuch, etc.1908-1924 (Box 3, Folder 82)
  - (8/1): Julie Braun-Vogelstein and Lilly Braun Correspondence, Mathilde v.Colomb, 1880-1886 (Box 3, Folder 83)
  - (8/2): Julie Braun-Vogelstein and Lilly Braun Correspondence Mathilde v. Colomb, 1887-1889 (Box 3, Folder 84)
  - (8/3): Julie Braun-Vogelstein and Lilly Braun Correspondence Mathilde v. Colomb, 1890- 93 (nr) (Box 3, Folder 85)
  - (8/4): Julie Braun-Vogelstein and Lilly Braun Correspondence Mathilde v. Colomb, 1894-1899 (n.r.) (Box 3, Folder 86)
  - (8/4): Julie Braun-Vogelstein and Lilly Braun Mrs.v. Kritschman(Lilly's mother), ca.1890-96 (n.r.) (Box 3, Folder 87)
  - (8/5): Julie Braun-Vogelstein and Lilly Braun miscellaneous Baronin v.Hermann, 1891- 98,1905-11 (Box 3, Folder 88)
  - (8/6): Julie Braun-Vogelstein and Lilly Braun miscellaneous Clippings etc., 1891-1910; 1965 (nr) (Box 3, Folder 89)
  - (8/7): Julie Braun-Vogelstein and Lilly Braun Obituaries,mostly Clippings, 1893-1916,1965 (nr) (Box 3, Folder 90)
  - Julie Braun-Vogelstein and Lilly Braun Obituaries Scrapbook w. clippings, 1916 (Box 3, Folder 91)
  - (9/1): Julie Braun-Vogelstein and Lilly Braun Correspondence Prof. Georg v.Gizycki, 1891- 93 (n.r.) (Box 3, Folder 92)
  - (9/2): Julie Braun-Vogelstein and Lilly Braun Correspondence to H.Braun, 1895-1896 (n.r.) (Box 3, Folder 93)